

Apartment 9, Bristol Road 488, Selly Oak, Birmingham, U.K., B29 6BD

🛘 (+44) 751-199-5018 | 🗷 ylhepower@gmail.com | 🛅 ylhepower | 🕞 Yinglong He | WeChat: yinglonghe

# Summary\_

Received bachelor's and master's degrees from Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST, ranked 9<sup>th</sup> in China). He is currently a Ph.D. candidate at the University of Birmingham (UoB), whose research interests are **optimization and control** of connected, autonomous and electrified vehicles, the intelligent transportation system (ITS), data mining and pattern recognition in driver and vehicle behaviors, and etc. He has expertise in **data analysis and visualization, scientific writing, web scraping, and etc**.

# **Education**

## **UoB (University of Birmingham)**

Birmingham, U.K.

Ph.D. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Sep. 2017 - 2021 (anticipated)

• 2017 - 2019: **School Scholarship** (TOP 1 %, £ 23 K per year), *School of Engineering, UoB*.

## **HUST (Huazhong University of Science and Technology)**

Wuhan, China

M.S. IN ENERGY AND POWER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2017

- 2016: National Scholarship for Graduate Students (TOP 0.2 %, ¥ 20 K), Chinese Ministry of Education.
- 2015: Guanghua Educational Scholarship (TOP 5 %, ¥ 1 K), Guanghua Education Foundation.
- 2015: Zhixing Educational Scholarship (TOP 5 %, ¥ 1 k), HUST.
- 2014 2017: First Prize of Academic Scholarship, HUST (TOP 10 %, ¥ 8 K per year), HUST.

### **HUST (Huazhong University of Science and Technology)**

Wuhan, China Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

B.S. IN ENERGY AND POWER ENGINEERING

• 2013: Outstanding Undergraduate Researcher Award (TOP 2 %), HUST.

- 2012 & 2013: National Endeavor Scholarship (TOP 1 %, ¥ 5 K per year), Chinese Ministry of Education.
- 2011: Merit Student (TOP 5 %), HUST.
- 2011: National Scholarship for Undergraduate Students (TOP 0.2 %, ¥ 8 K), Chinese Ministry of Education.

# Honors & Awards

## INTERNATIONAL

Best Simulation Application Paper Award, 99th Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board (TRB, the world's largest transportation research conference)

Washington, U.S.A

### **DOMESTIC**

2018	Finalist, "Chunhui Cup" Chinese Overseas Students Innovation and Entrepreneurship	Guangzhou, China
2013	2nd Prize, "Challenge Cup" Competition of Science and Technology in Hubei Province	Wuhan, China
2012	1st Place, The 1st WHU (Wuhan University) - HUST Dragon Boat Race	Wuhan, China

# **Experience**

# **European Commission - Joint Research Centre (JRC)**

Ispra, Italy

Apr. 2019 - June 2020

EXTERNAL EXPERT

- Created a database of vehicle specifications obtained from web scraping.
- Conducted experiments for evaluating advanced driver assistance systems (ADAS) such as adaptive cruise control (ACC).
   Installed the vehicle test equipment for reading live data from the CAN bus, the OBD II, the GPS module, and etc.
- Developed a dynamics-based car-following model (MFC) for electrified vehicles.
- Contributed to the development of a Python library (https://pypi.org/project/co2mpas-driver) for microsimulation.
- Published four journal articles and one conference paper; received the best paper award from an international conference.

## Laboratory of Connected and Autonomous Systems for Electrified Vehicles (CASE-V), UoB

Birmingham, U.K.

Engineering Lab Assistant

Jan. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Provided an IoT (internet of things) platform to connect the real-time digital models to real vehicles and powertrain components.
- Built the vehicle co-simulation system with hardware in the loop (HiL) and integrated MATLAB/Simulink, AVL PUMA and IPG CarMaker.

## **Mechanical Engineering, UoB**

Birmingham, U.K.

TEACHING ASSISTANT Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2019

• Assisted **courses** such as Engineering Mathematics, Vehicle Engineering, CFD & FEA, C++, Python, MATLAB/Simulink, and etc.

AUGUST 11, 2020 YINGLONG HE · CURRICULUM VITAE 1 OF 2

#### **Association of British Chinese Professors (ABCP)**

EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT Mar. 2020

• Contributed to the design of the association logo, posters, banners, and etc.

• Designed **brochures and programs** for the first & second ABCP annual meetings.

#### School of Energy and Power Engineering, HUST

HEAD OF THE GRADUATE STUDENTS UNION

· Managed a committee of 50+ people, which served and represented 800+ graduate students.

Wuhan, China

Wuhan, China

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2015

Birmingham, U.K.

#### State Key Laboratory of Coal Combustion (SKLCC)

IT and PC Consultant

Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2016

· Built and maintained a website (http://xu.energy.hust.edu.cn/) for the purpose of laboratory information management.

# Shanghai, China

Shanghai Electric Group Co., Ltd

Intern Engineer

Aug. 2013 - Sep. 2013

A traineeship for the design, manufacture and sale of power generation equipment.

# **Skills**

**Research interests** Connected, automated, and electrified vehicles; intelligent transportation system (ITS); multiobjective optimization;

artificial intelligence(AI); machine learning (ML); pattern recognition; and data mining.

**Programming** Python, MATLAB/Simulink, C++, and LaTeX.

**Languages** Chinese (native) and English (professional working proficiency).

**Software** Microsoft office, Photoshop, InDesign, CAD, CFD, AWS DynamoDB/Lambda/EC2/S3 and etc.

# **Publications**

#### JOURNAL ARTICLES

- 1. Y. He, C. Wang, Q. Zhou, J. Li, M. Makridis, H. Williams, G. Lu\*, and H. Xu\*. Multiobjective component sizing of a hybrid ethanol-electric vehicle propulsion system. *Applied Energy*. 2020 May 15;266:114843. (SCI, IF = 8.426, JCR Q1)
- 2. **Y. He**, Q. Zhou, M. Makridis, K. Mattas, J. Li, H. Williams, and H. Xu\*. Multiobjective co-optimization of cooperative adaptive cruise control and energy management strategy for PHEVs. *IEEE Transactions on Transportation Electrification*. 2020 Feb 17. (**SCI, IF = 5.270, JCR Q1**)
- 3. Y. He, M. Makridis\*, G. Fontaras, K. Mattas, H. Xu, and B. Ciuffo. The energy impact of adaptive cruise control in real-world highway multiple-car-following scenarios. European Transport Research Review. 2020 Dec;12(1):1-11. (SCI, IF = 1.727, JCR Q3)
- 4. **Y. He**, M. Makridis\*, K. Mattas, G. Fontaras, B. Ciuffo, and H. Xu. Introducing electrified vehicle dynamics in traffic simulation. *Transportation Research Record*. 2020. (**SCI, IF = 0.748, JCR Q4**)
- 5. Y. He, X. Gao\*, Y. Qiao, and M. Xu\*. Occurrence forms of key ash-forming elements in defatted microalgal biomass. *Fuel.* 2017 Jul 15;200:182-185. (SCI, IF = 4.908, JCR O1)
- 6. **Y. He**, D. Yu\*, T. Lei, W. Lv, and M. Xu\*. Chemical looping CO2/CH4 reforming using Fe-based oxygen carrier for syngas production. *Huagong Xuebao/CIESC Journal*. 2016;67(12):5222-5228.
- 7. Q. Zhou\*, **Y. He**, D. Zhao, J. Li, Y. Li, H. Williams, and H. Xu. Modified particle swarm optimization with chaotic attraction strategy for modular design of hybrid powertrains. *IEEE Transactions on Transportation Electrification*. 2020.
- 8. B. Shuai, Q. Zhou\*, J. Li, **Y. He**, Z. Li, H. Williams, H. Xu, and S. Shuai. Heuristic action execution for energy efficient charge-sustaining control of connected hybrid vehicles with model-free double Q-learning. *Applied Energy*. 2020 Jun 1;267:114900.
- 9. J. Li, Q. Zhou, Y. He, H. Williams, and H. Xu\*. Driver-identified supervisory control system of hybrid electric vehicles based on spectrum-guided fuzzy feature extraction. *IEEE Transactions on Fuzzy Systems*. 2020 Feb 11.
- 10. Q. Zhou, J. Li, B. Shuai, H. Williams, Y. He, Z. Li, H. Xu\*, and F. Yan. Multi-step reinforcement learning for model-free predictive energy management of an electrified off-highway vehicle. *Applied Energy*. 2019 Dec 1;255:113755.
- 11. J. Li, Q. Zhou, **Y. He**, B. Shuai, Z. Li, H. Williams, and H. Xu\*. Dual-loop online intelligent programming for driver-oriented predict energy management of plug-in hybrid electric vehicles. *Applied Energy*. 2019 Nov 1;253:113617.

### **CONFERENCE PAPERS**

1. Y. He, B. Ciuffo\*, Q. Zhou, M. Makridis, K. Mattas, J. Li, Z. Li, F. Yan, and H. Xu. Adaptive cruise control strategies implemented on experimental vehicles: A review. 9th IFAC SymJposium on Advances in Automotive Control AAC. 2019 Jan 1;52(5):21-27.

#### **PATENTS**

1. D. Yu\*, Y. He, M. Xu, W. Lv, and B. Fan. A novel process for using CO2 in the production of dimethyl ether. China Patent (ZL 2014 1 0853700.5). June 22, 2016.